<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.xsl"?>
<plan plan-format="1.0" xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      name="Project Name">
   <release projectid="modeling.emft.compare" version="1.0.0"/>
   <introduction>
     <html:div>
This document lays out the feature and API set for the
1.0.0 release of the EMF Compare project.
This project plan inherits from the Modeling Project Plan,
which should be referenced when consulting this individual project plan.
     </html:div>
   </introduction>
   <release_deliverables>
     <html:div>
The release deliverables have the same form as is found in most Eclipse projects, namely:
       <ul>
         <li>
EMF Compare source code release, 
available as versions tagged with "R1_0" in the project's CVS repository.
         </li>
         <li>
EMF Compare SDK,
which includes runtime, sources, examples, and documentation,
and is available as a download or on the update site.
         </li>
         <li>
EMF Compare  binary distribution,
available as a download or on the update site.
         </li>
         <li>
EMF Compare tests
available as a download.
         </li>
       </ul>
     </html:div>
   </release_deliverables>
   <release_milestones>
      <preamble>
         <html:div>
Release milestones occur at roughly 6 week intervals 
and follow the Platform release milestone by the Galileo-established +2 delta interval.
The final EMF Compare 1.0 release will available simultaneously 
with the 3.5 release of the Platform and all the other Galileo projects.
         </html:div>
      </preamble>
<milestone date="12/29/2008" milestone="M4"></milestone>
<milestone date="02/06/2009" milestone="M5"></milestone>
<milestone date="03/18/2009" milestone="M6"><html:div>API freeze</html:div></milestone>
<milestone date="05/05/2009" milestone="M7"><html:div>Feature Freeze</html:div></milestone>
<milestone date="05/19/2009" milestone="RC1"></milestone>
<milestone date="05/26/2009" milestone="RC2"></milestone>
<milestone date="06/02/2009" milestone="RC3"></milestone>
<milestone date="06/09/2009" milestone="RC4"></milestone>
<milestone date="06/16/2009" milestone="RC5"></milestone>
<milestone date="06/28/2009" milestone="1.0.0"></milestone>
      <postamble>
        <html:div>
EMF Compare will produce maintenance releases to align with the Ganymede Service Releases
which includes the Eclipse Platform's 3.4.1 and 3.4.2 releases.
EMF Compare may produce additional interim maintenance releases.  
Maintenance releases will only be published if they contain new fixes.
          <ul>
            <li>
Friday, September 26, 2008 - EMF Compare 0.8.1 maintenance release for Ganymede Service Release 1.
            </li>
            <li>
Friday, February 28, 2009 - EMF Compare  0.8.2 maintenance release for Ganymede Service Release 2.
            </li>
            <li>
Version numbers are subject to change should there be be any additional maintenance releases.
A list of the issues addressed for the 0.8.x maintenance stream 
are available in the Release notes : http://www.eclipse.org/modeling/emft/news/relnotes.php?project=compare&version=0.8.x.
            </li>
          </ul> 
        </html:div>
      </postamble>
    </release_milestones>
    <target_environments>
      <html:div>
In order to remain current, each Eclipse release targets reasonably current versions of the underlying operating environments. 
The EMF Compare project depends upon on the Platform,which is mostly "pure" Java™.The 3.5 release of the Eclipse Platform Project 
is written and compiled against version 1.4 of the Java Platform APIs,  and targeted to run on version 1.4 of the Java Runtime Environment, Standard Edition. 
EMF Compare rely on EMF Core which is written and compiled against version 1.5 of the Java Platform APIs.,
EMF Compare relies on Java 5. 
Eclipse Platform SDK 3.5 will be tested and validated on a number of reference platforms. 
EMF Compare  will be tested and validated against a subset of those listed for the platform.

Given that there is no operating system dependent code in EMF Compare, it's expected that EMF Compare will work anywhere the Eclipse Platform does.
     </html:div>
     <internationalization>
          <html:div>
The Eclipse Platform is designed as the basis for internationalized products. 
The user interface elements provided by the Eclipse SDK components, 
including dialogs and error messages,
are externalized. 
The English strings are provided as the default resource bundles. 
Similarly, the EMF Compare project will externalize all its user interface elements,
provide English strings for them in its default bundles, 
and localize a subset of the locales offered by the Platform. 
The download page will provide the details as the become available.
          </html:div>
     </internationalization>
   </target_environments>
   <compatibility_with_previous_releases>
       <html:div>
Compatibility of Release 1.0.0: 
The EMF Compare project will be developed in parallel, 
and released simultaneously, 
with the following project. 
         <ul>
         <li>
Eclipse Platform SDK version 3.5
           </li>
           <li>
EMF Core 2.5
           </li>
        </ul>
Each milestone version of the EMF Compare project 
will be compatible with the corresponding milestone for this project 
and will be delivered within the appropriate time offset.


The ultimate EMF Compare release will be compatible with the released version of its dependencies
and will publish binary and source compatibilities with migration guides on subsequent releases.
       </html:div>
   </compatibility_with_previous_releases>
   <themes_and_priorities>
     <preamble>
         <html:div>
A list of project goals and agreed upon implementation time frames is found in this document.
For the milestones listed in this document, 
a set of overall themes is used to indicate what major set of functionalities is expected to be the focus of each.
These themes are presented below, 
while the goals of the associated Bugzilla entries are available for more detailed information.
         </html:div>
     </preamble>
       <theme name="Incubation Exit">
            <description>
                <html:div>
                The EMF Compare project will provide all the required "must do's " to exit it's incubation status.
                </html:div>
            </description>
            <committed
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </committed>
            <proposed
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </proposed>
            <deferred
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </deferred>
        </theme>
        <theme name="Graphical Modelers Integration">
            <description>
                <html:div>
                The EMF Compare project is meant to be used and integrated in other component. Work will be done to make sure that
                a client is able to integrate the compare support in a specific graphical modeler based on GMF.
                </html:div>
            </description>
            <committed
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </committed>
            <proposed
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </proposed>
            <deferred
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </deferred>
        </theme>
        <theme name="Patch Model">
            <description>
                <html:div>
                Pursuing his goal to achieve the same level of features for models as the Text comparison provides for the classical languages , the 1.0 release will 
                bring a self contained changeset model capturing differences on two models. Using this model one will be able to apply the changes on another model, 
                just as the text patch system.                 
                </html:div>
            </description>
            <committed
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </committed>
            <proposed
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </proposed>
            <deferred
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </deferred>
        </theme>
        <theme name="ResourceSet Matching">
            <description>
                <html:div>
                The 1.0 release will bring the possibility to match whole resource sets instead of just resources.
                </html:div>
            </description>
            <committed
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </committed>
            <proposed
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </proposed>
            <deferred
                bugzilla="TBD">
            </deferred>
         </theme>
   </themes_and_priorities>
   <appendix name="Legal Notices">
        <html:div>
          <ul>
            <li>
Java is a trademark or a registered trademark of Sun Microsystems, Inc.
            </li>
            <li>
All other products or company names are mentioned for identification purposes only,
and may be trademarks or service marks of their respective owners.
            </li>
          </ul>
        </html:div>
   </appendix>
</plan>
