<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.xsl"?>
<plan plan-format="1.0" xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      name="Teneo">
   <release projectid="modeling.emf.teneo" version="1.2"/>
   <introduction>
     <html:div>
This document lays out the planned features for the next major release
of the model-driven Object Relational Mapping Framework Teneo, version 1.2. This project plan inherits from the Modeling
Project Plan, which should be referenced when consulting this
individual project plan.
     </html:div>
   </introduction>
   <release_deliverables>
     <html:div>
The release deliverables have the same form as is found in most Eclipse projects, namely:
<html:ul>
<html:li>Teneo SDK (includes Mapping Providers for different ORM Tools, Examples, Documentation and Source).</html:li>
<html:li>Teneo Examples (contains the Teneo examples models and tutorials.</html:li>
<html:li>Teneo Tests (contains the testcases).</html:li>
</html:ul>
     </html:div>
   </release_deliverables>
    <release_milestones>
        <preamble>
            <p>
            	Teneo will participate in Helios from the M3 Milestone. From then 
                Teneo Milestones follow the Eclipse release milestones by an offset of 2 as set by the
                <a href="htt//wiki.eclipse.org/Helios#Milestones_and_Release_Candidates">Helios release schedule.</a>.
                Teneo will have weekly Maintenance releases to solve any issues reported in the previous week. 
                Maintenance releases are only done if there are issues to solve. 
            </p>
            <p>Note: The following are preliminary dates subject to change.</p>
        </preamble>
        <milestone
            date="11/06/2009"
            milestone="M3">
            <p>M3 milestone</p>
        </milestone>
                <milestone
            date="12/11/2009"
            milestone="M4">
            <p>M4 milestone</p>
        </milestone>
		<milestone
            date="1/29/2010"
            milestone="M5">
            <p>M5 milestone</p>
        </milestone>
        <milestone
            date="3/12/2010"
            milestone="M6">
            <p>M6 milestone</p>
        </milestone>
        <milestone
            date="4/30/2010"
            milestone="M7">
            <p>M7 milestone</p>
        </milestone>
        <milestone
            date="5/14/2010"
            milestone="RC1">
            <p>RC1 milestone</p>
        </milestone>
        <milestone
            date="5/21/2010"
            milestone="RC2">
            <p>RC2 milestone</p>

        </milestone>
        <milestone
            date="5/28/2010"
            milestone="RC3">
            <p>RC3 milestone</p>
        </milestone>
        <milestone
            date="6/04/2010"
            milestone="RC4">
            <p>RC4 milestone</p>
        </milestone>
        <milestone
            date="6/11/2010"
            milestone="Final Build">
            <p>Final Build.</p>
        </milestone>
        <milestone
            date="06/23/2010"
            milestone="GA">
            <p>GA</p>
        </milestone>
        <postamble />
    </release_milestones>
   <target_environments>
     <html:div>
In order to remain current, each Eclipse release targets reasonably
current versions of the underlying operating environments. The Teneo 
Project depends upon on the
Platform and other projects, which are mostly "pure" Java<html:sup>TM</html:sup>. Teneo
will target the same Java version as EMF Core, which currently requires
Java 5. Eclipse Platform SDK 3.5 will be tested and validated on a
number of reference platforms. Teneo will be tested and validated
against a subset of those listed for the platform.
     </html:div>
     <internationalization>
          <html:div>
Teneo is a runtime technology, most of the 
components having no user interface. The remaining user interface 
parts of Teneo are considered exemplary and thus no attention has been 
paid to externalize them for internationalization.
          </html:div>
     </internationalization>
   </target_environments>
   <compatibility_with_previous_releases>
       <html:div>
Teneo will be 
backward compatible for the ORM tools supported in previous releases. Mapping 
stability/backward compatibility (generated the same mapping in new releases) 
is in this respect far more important than
binary compatibility.
       </html:div>
   </compatibility_with_previous_releases>
   <themes_and_priorities>
     <preamble>
         <html:div>
A list of project requirements and agreed upon
implementation time frames is found in this document. For the
milestones listed in this document, a set of overall themes is used
to indicate what major set of functionalities is to be concentrated
on for each. These themes are presented below, while the requirements
document and associated Bugzilla entries are left to those wanting
more detailed information on each.
         </html:div>
     </preamble>
    <theme name="Improvements and Consolidation">
      <description>
        <html:div>
			<p>In 1.5 Teneo will have a completely new mapping strategy <a href="http://www.elver.org/hibernate/eav_mapping.html">EAV</a>.</p> 
			<p>Other improvements are mainly focused on further extending the support for Hibernate annotations.</p>
        </html:div>
      </description>
            <committed
                bugzilla="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/buglist.cgi?bug_file_loc=&amp;bug_file_loc_type=allwordssubstr&amp;bug_id=&amp;bugidtype=include&amp;chfieldfrom=&amp;chfieldto=Now&amp;chfieldvalue=&amp;classification=Modeling&amp;component=Teneo&amp;email1=&amp;email2=&amp;emailtype1=substring&amp;emailtype2=substring&amp;field0-0-0=noop&amp;keywords=&amp;keywords_type=allwords&amp;longdesc=&amp;longdesc_type=allwordssubstr&amp;product=EMF&amp;query_format=advanced&amp;short_desc=Helios&amp;short_desc_type=allwordssubstr&amp;status_whiteboard=&amp;status_whiteboard_type=allwordssubstr&amp;type0-0-0=noop&amp;value0-0-0=&amp;version=1.2&amp;votes=&amp;title=Bug%20List">
            </committed>
    </theme>
   </themes_and_priorities>
</plan>
