<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.xsl"?>
<plan plan-format="1.0" xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      name="Project Name">
   <release projectid="modeling.m2m" version="Helios"/>
   <introduction>
     <html:div>
<html:p>This document lays out the feature and API set for the 
third release of the Eclipse QVT Declarative (QVTd) 
Project, version 0.9.0.</html:p>
<html:p>
<html:i><html:b>Note</html:b> that, since the 
<html:a href="http://www.omg.org/cgi-bin/doc?ptc/08-04-03pdf">OMG QVT 1.0</html:a>
standard suffers from significant ambiguities and conflicts making a compliant implementation impossible,
<html:b>QVTd</html:b>release is best endeavours to establish a coherent interpretation 
of the OMG QVT 1.1 standard.</html:i>
</html:p>
<html:p>
</html:p>
<html:p>
</html:p>
     </html:div>
   </introduction>
   <release_deliverables>
     <html:div>The release deliverables for the QVTd release have the same form as 
is found in most Eclipse projects, namely:<html:ul>
<html:li>QVTd SDK (includes runtime, sources, examples, and documentation) (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
<html:li>QVTd runtime binary distribution (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
<html:li>QVTd stand-alone binary distribution (downloadable).</html:li>
<html:li>QVTd tests (downloadable)</html:li>
<html:li>QVTd examples (downloadable)</html:li>
</html:ul>QVTd 0.9.0 source code will be available as versions tagged "Juno" in the project's GIT repository.
</html:div>
   </release_deliverables>
   <release_milestones>
      <preamble>
         <html:div>Release milestones occurring at roughly 6 week intervals and follow the 
Platform milestone releases by approximately 1 week.</html:div>
      </preamble>
<milestone date="Wednesday 27 June 2012" milestone="Juno"></milestone>
      <postamble><html:div>QVTd may produce interim maintenance releases in addition to these in
order to satisfy clients requests.</html:div></postamble>
   </release_milestones>
   <target_environments>
     <html:div>In order to remain current, each Eclipse release targets reasonably
 current versions of the underlying operating environments. The Eclipse
 QVT Declarative (QVTd) project depends upon on the
 Platform and other projects, which are mostly "pure" Java. The 4.2
 release of the Eclipse Platform Project is written and compiled
 against version 5.0 of the Java Platform APIs, and targeted to run on
 version 5.0 of the Java Runtime Environment, Standard Edition. M2 QVTd will target the same Java version as EMF, OCL and UML2, which currently require
 Java 5. Eclipse Platform SDK 3.6 will be tested and validated on a
 number of reference platforms. QVTd will be tested and validated
 against a subset of those listed for the platform.</html:div>
     <internationalization>
          <html:div>The Eclipse Platform is designed as the basis
 for internationalized products. The user interface elements provided
 by the Eclipse SDK components, including dialogs and error messages,
are externalized. The English strings are provided as the default
 resource bundles. As a result, the QVTd project will provide English strings in its default bundles and be 
localized to a subset of those locales offered by the Platform. This 
plan will be updated to indicate which locales will be provided and
the time frame for availability.</html:div>
     </internationalization>
   </target_environments>
   <compatibility_with_previous_releases>
       <html:div>The QVTd project
 will be developed in parallel, and released simultaneously, with the 
following projects.<html:ul>
    <html:li>Eclipse Platform SDK version 4.2</html:li>
    <html:li>Eclipse Modeling Framework (EMF) version 2.8</html:li>
    <html:li>Model Development Tools (MDT) UML2 version 4.0</html:li>
    <html:li>Model Development Tools (MDT) OCL version 4.0</html:li>
</html:ul>
<html:p>QVTd 0.7.0 was never formally released with a stable build or update site.</html:p>
<html:p>QVTd 0.8.0 was only formally released as an RC1 build.</html:p>
<html:p>
</html:p>
       </html:div>
   </compatibility_with_previous_releases>
   <themes_and_priorities>
     <preamble>
         <html:div>
A list of project requirements and agreed upon
implementation time frames is found in this document. For the
milestones listed in this document, a set of overall themes is used
to indicate what major set of functionalities is to be concentrated
on for each. These themes are presented below, while the requirements
document and associated Bugzilla entries are left to those wanting
more detailed information on each.
         </html:div>
     </preamble>
        <theme name="Execution">
            <description>
                <html:div>This theme addresses the major prevailing project deficiency.</html:div>
            </description>
        </theme>
   </themes_and_priorities>
   <appendix name="Legal Notices">
        <html:div>
<html:ul>
<html:li>Java is a trademark or a registered trademark of Oracle Corporation.</html:li>
<html:li>QVT, UML, OCL and OMG are trademarks or registered trademark of the Object Management Group, Inc.</html:li>
<html:li>All other products or company names are mentioned for identification purposes only, and
 may be trademarks or service marks of their respective owners.</html:li>
</html:ul>
        </html:div>
   </appendix>
</plan>