<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!--<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="project-plan-render.xsl"?>-->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.xsl"?>
<plan plan-format="1.0" xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      name="EMF Index">
   <release projectid="modeling.emf.emfindex" version="0.7.0"/>
   <introduction>
     This document lays out the feature and API set for the first release of the EMF Index component, version 0.8.0, of the EMFT Project.  
     This project plan inherits from the Modeling Project Plan, which should be referenced when consulting this individual project plan.
   </introduction>
<release_deliverables>
     <html:p>
    The release deliverables have the same form as is found in most Eclipse projects, namely:
<html:ul>
<html:li>EMF Index source code release, available as versions tagged "R0_8" in the project's CVS repository.</html:li>
<html:li>EMF Index (includes runtime, with sources, examples, and documentation) (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
<html:li>EMF Index runtime binary distribution (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
<html:li>EMF Index tests (downloadable and update site)</html:li>
</html:ul>
  </html:p>
    </release_deliverables>
   <release_milestones>
      <preamble>
      <html:p>Release milestone occurring at roughly 6 week intervals and follow the Platform milestone releases by approximately 2 weeks; 
      that is, until the final 3.6 release of the Platform, upon which EMF Index and other projects will release simultaneously. 
      As EMF Index is dependent upon the EMF, and other projects, which are scheduled to release milestones within 1 week of Platform milestones, 
      EMF Index will deliver its milestones within the following week. 
      It is anticipated that EMF Index will synchronize its release milestones with the Galileo release schedule.
       </html:p>
      </preamble>
      <milestone date="10/02/2009" milestone="M2"></milestone>
      <milestone date="11/10/2009" milestone="M3"></milestone>
      <milestone date="12/15/2009" milestone="M4"></milestone>
      <milestone date="02/02/2010" milestone="M5"></milestone>
      <milestone date="03/16/2010" milestone="M6"><html:p>API freeze</html:p></milestone>
      <milestone date="05/04/2010" milestone="M7"></milestone>
      <milestone date="05/18/2009" milestone="RC1"></milestone>
      <milestone date="05/25/2009" milestone="RC2"></milestone>
      <milestone date="06/01/2009" milestone="RC3"></milestone>
      <milestone date="06/08/2009" milestone="RC4"></milestone>
      <milestone date="06/15/2009" milestone="RC5"><html:p>Last build</html:p></milestone>
      <milestone date="06/23/2009" milestone="0.8.0"></milestone>
   </release_milestones>
   <target_environments>
     <html:div>In order to remain current, each Eclipse release targets reasonably current versions of the underlying operating environments.
The EMF Index project depends upon on the Platform and other projects, which are mostly "pure" Java. 
The 3.6 release of the Eclipse Platform Project is written and compiled against version 1.4 of the Java Platform APIs, 
and targeted to run on version 1.4 of the Java Runtime Environment, Standard Edition. 
EMF Index will target the same Java version as EMF, which currently requires Java 5.
Eclipse Platform SDK 3.6 will be tested and validated on a number of reference platforms. 
EMF Index will be tested and validated against a subset of those listed for the platform. 
Those available will be presented on the project download site.</html:div>
     <internationalization>
       <html:div>The Eclipse Platform is designed as the basis for internationalized products. 
       The user interface elements provided by the Eclipse SDK components, including dialogs and error messages, are externalized. 
       The English strings are provided as the default resource bundles. 
       As a result, the EMF Index project will provide English strings in its default bundles and be localized to a subset of those locales offered by the Platform. 
       This plan will be updated to indicate which locales will be provided and the time frame for availability.</html:div>
     </internationalization>
   </target_environments>
   <themes_and_priorities>
     <preamble>
         <html:div>EMF Index will target the following themes:</html:div>
     </preamble>
     <theme name="Scaling Up">
        <description><html:div>EMF Index should allow the development of scalable modeling tools, managing a large number of interconnected models and allowing fast queries on them.</html:div></description>
     </theme>
     <theme name="Design for Extensibility">
        <description><html:div>EMF Index will allow domain-specific extension and optimization.</html:div></description>
     </theme>
   </themes_and_priorities>
   <compatibility_with_previous_releases>
     <html:div>This is the first Eclipse release of EMF Index. </html:div>
   </compatibility_with_previous_releases>
 </plan>