<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.xsl"?>
<!--<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="project-plan-render.xsl"?>-->
<plan plan-format="1.0" xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      name="EMF Facet">
   <release projectid="modeling.emft.emf-facet" version="0.2.0"/>
   <introduction>
     <html:div>
     	This document lays out the feature and API set for the next release of EMF Facet (EMFT Project), version 0.2.0. This project plan inherits from the Modeling Project Plan, which should be referenced when consulting this individual project plan.
     </html:div>
   </introduction>
   <release_deliverables>
     <html:div>
     	The release deliverables have the same form as is found in most Eclipse projects, namely: 
     	<html:ul>
     		<html:li>EMFT EMF Facet SDK (includes runtime, sources, examples, tests and documentation) (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
		<html:li>EMFT EMF Facet runtime binary distribution (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
		<html:li>EMFT EMF Facet documentation (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
     		<html:li>EMFT EMF Facet examples (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
     		<!--
     		<html:li>An update site providing access to all the plug-ins, sources and documentation.</html:li>
     		<html:li>A downloadable archive of this update site</html:li>
     		-->
     	</html:ul>
     	Note that Eclipse EMFT EMF Facet 0.2.0 will primarily target Eclipse 3.8 and is tested against Eclipse 4.2.
     </html:div>
   </release_deliverables>
   <release_milestones>
      <preamble>
         <html:div>
         	Release milestones occur at roughly 6 week intervals and follow the Platform milestone releases by approximately 1 week; that is, until the final 4.2 release of the Platform, upon which EMFT EMF Facet and other projects will release simultaneously. As EMFT EMF Facet depends on other projects, it will deliver its milestones at the +2 schedule in accordance with the schedule below. 
         </html:div>
      </preamble>
      <milestone date="08/16/2011" milestone="M1"></milestone>
      <milestone date="09/27/2011" milestone="M2"></milestone>
      <milestone date="11/08/2011" milestone="M3"></milestone>
      <milestone date="12/16/2011" milestone="M4"></milestone>
      <milestone date="02/31/2012" milestone="M5"></milestone>
      <milestone date="03/20/2012" milestone="M6"><html:b>(API Freeze)</html:b></milestone>
      <milestone date="05/08/2012" milestone="M7"><html:b>(Feature Freeze)</html:b></milestone>
      <milestone date="05/22/2012" milestone="RC1"></milestone>
      <milestone date="05/29/2012" milestone="RC2"></milestone>
      <milestone date="06/05/2012" milestone="RC3"></milestone>
      <milestone date="06/12/2012" milestone="RC4"></milestone>
      <milestone date="06/27/2012" milestone="Juno"></milestone>
      <postamble>
      	<html:div>
		EMFT EMF Facet will produce maintenance releases to align with the Indigo SR releases, that includes the Eclipse Platform 3.7.1 and 3.7.2 releases. EMFT EMF Facet may produce interim maintenance releases in addition to these in order to satisfy client requests. 
			<html:ul>
     			<html:li>Friday, September 23, 2012 - EMFT EMF Facet 0.1.1 maintenance release (Indigo Service Release 1)</html:li>
			<html:li>Friday, February 24, 2012 - EMFT EMF Facet 0.1.2 maintenance release (Indigo Service Release 2)</html:li>
     		</html:ul>
		</html:div>
	  </postamble>
   </release_milestones>
   <target_environments>
     <html:div>
     In order to remain current, each Eclipse release targets reasonably current versions of the underlying operating environments. The Eclipse EMFT EMF Facet project depends upon on the Platform and other projects, which are mostly "pure" Java. The 4.2 release of the Eclipse Platform Project is written and compiled against version 5.0 of the Java Platform APIs, and targeted to run on version 5.0 of the Java Runtime Environment, Standard Edition. EMF Facet will target the same Java version as EMF, which currently also requires Java 5. Eclipse Platform SDK 4.2 will be tested and validated on a number of reference platforms. EMFT EMF Facet will be tested and validated against a subset of those listed for the platform. 
     </html:div>
     <internationalization>
          <html:div>
         	 The Eclipse Platform is designed as the basis for internationalized products. The user interface elements provided by the Eclipse SDK components, including dialogs and error messages, are externalized. The English strings are provided as the default resource bundles. As a result, the EMFT EMF Facet project will provide English strings in its default bundles and be localized to a subset of those locales offered by the Platform. 
          </html:div>
     </internationalization>
   </target_environments>
   <compatibility_with_previous_releases>
   		<html:div>
       		Compatibility of Release 0.2.0: The EMFT EMF Facet project will be developed in parallel, and released simultaneously, with the following projects. As stated above, each milestone release of the EMFT EMF Facet project will be compatible with the corresponding milestones for each of these projects, and delivered the appropriate offset. 
       		<html:ul>
     			<html:li>Eclipse Platform SDK version 4.2</html:li>
     			<html:li>Eclipse Modeling Framework (EMF) version 2.8</html:li>
     			<html:li>Eclipse Model Development Tools (MDT) UML2 version 4.0</html:li>
     		</html:ul>	
       	</html:div>
   </compatibility_with_previous_releases>
   <themes_and_priorities>
     <preamble>
         <html:div>
         	A list of project requirements and agreed upon implementation time frames is found in this document. For the milestones listed in this document, a set of overall themes is used to indicate what major set of functionalities is to be concentrated on for each. These themes are presented below, while the requirements document and associated Bugzilla entries are left to those wanting more detailed information on each. 
         </html:div>
     </preamble>
     <theme name="Restructuring">
        <description>
        	<html:div>
			The main goals of this year is are to:<ul>
				<li>to finish the migration of features from MDT MoDisco (Query Manager and Facet Manager components) to EMF Facet ;</li>
				<li>to merge the existing versions of the EMF Facet framework.</li></ul>
			This restructuring is a priority otherwise we will not be able to provide stable and usable software. That's why non critical bugs will be fixed after this restructuring.
        		
			</html:div>
        </description> 
        <committed bugzilla="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/buglist.cgi?priority=P1;priority=P2;priority=P4;short_desc=%5BRestructuring%5D;field0-0-0=flagtypes.name;query_format=advanced;bug_status=UNCONFIRMED;bug_status=NEW;bug_status=ASSIGNED;bug_status=REOPENED;bug_status=RESOLVED;bug_status=VERIFIED;bug_status=CLOSED;short_desc_type=allwordssubstr;type0-0-0=substring;value0-0-0=juno%2B;product=EMFT.facet"/>
      	<proposed bugzilla="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/buglist.cgi?priority=P5;query_format=advanced;short_desc=%5BRestructuring%5D;field0-0-0=flagtypes.name;short_desc_type=allwordssubstr;type0-0-0=substring;value0-0-0=juno%2B;product=EMFT.facet"/>
      	<deferred bugzilla="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/buglist.cgi?priority=P5;query_format=advanced;short_desc=%5BRestructuring%5D;field0-0-0=flagtypes.name;short_desc_type=allwordssubstr;type0-0-0=notsubstring;value0-0-0=juno%2B;product=EMFT.facet"/>
     </theme>
     <theme name="Service, Support and Maintenance">
        <description>
        	<html:div>
Service and support will take priority over new development work, however this year the restructuring has the highest priority. Commitments and schedules are subject to arbitrary change, slippage, or even deferral.         	
			</html:div>
        </description> 
        <committed bugzilla="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/buglist.cgi?priority=P1;priority=P2;priority=P4;query_format=advanced;field0-0-0=flagtypes.name;bug_severity=blocker;bug_severity=critical;bug_severity=major;bug_severity=normal;bug_severity=minor;bug_severity=trivial;type0-0-0=substring;value0-0-0=juno%2B;product=EMFT.facet"/>
      	<proposed bugzilla="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/buglist.cgi?priority=P5;query_format=advanced;field0-0-0=flagtypes.name;bug_severity=blocker;bug_severity=critical;bug_severity=major;bug_severity=normal;bug_severity=minor;bug_severity=trivial;type0-0-0=substring;value0-0-0=juno%2B;product=EMFT.facet"/>
      	<deferred bugzilla="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/buglist.cgi?priority=P5;query_format=advanced;field0-0-0=flagtypes.name;bug_severity=blocker;bug_severity=critical;bug_severity=major;bug_severity=normal;bug_severity=minor;bug_severity=trivial;type0-0-0=notsubstring;value0-0-0=juno%2B;product=EMFT.facet"/>
     </theme>
     
     
     <!--
     <postamble>
     	<html:div>
        </html:div>	
     </postamble>
     -->
   </themes_and_priorities>
   <appendix name="Legal Notices">
   	 <html:div>
     	<html:ul>
     		<html:li>Java is a trademark or a registered trademark of Oracle and Sun, Inc.</html:li>
     		<html:li>UML is trademark or registered trademark of the Object Management Group, Inc.</html:li>
     		<html:li>All other products or company names are mentioned for identification purposes only, and may be trademarks or service marks of their respective owners.</html:li>
     	</html:ul>	
     </html:div>  
   </appendix>	
 </plan>
